# LAIMA PILELIENĖ

Klaipėda · +37067074438 pileliene.laima@gmail.com



I have expertise in Biochemistry and Molecular Biology fields, with 3+ years of laboratory work experience, focusing on various laboratory experiments and methods. During my career I have gained experience in Lean methodology, teamwork and continuous improvement driven by goal orientation.

## **EXPERIENCE**

### **FEBRUARY 2018 – JUNE 2019**

### JUNIOR SCIENTIST, THERMO FISHER SCIENTIFIC BALTICS

Independent experiment planning and execution (E-gel, NGS, qPCR). New product research and development (PCR, RT-qPCR, qPCR). Analytical method development and validation, documentation preparation, product design verification and validation. Experimental data analysis and presentation to cross-functional team members and managers.

#### MAY 2014 - SEPTEMBER 2014 & MAY 2015 - SEPTEMBER 2015

### JUNIOR BIOANALYST, THERMO FISHER SCIENTIFIC BALTICS

Quality control laboratory: testing new product by various protocols and experiments (PCR, qPCR, Spectrometry, DNR, Protein electrophoresis, endotoxin testing, measuring enzymatic activities (by spectrophotometry, radiolabeling, fluorescence), enzymatic plate assay (ELISA)). Documentation preparation.

#### OCTOBER 2014 – FEBRUARY 2018

# **INTERN, THERMO FISHER SCIENTIFIC BALTICS**

Designing and performing experiments by various laboratory equipment. Experimental data analysis, summarizing and presentation.

# **EDUCATION**

#### 2016 - 2018

### MOLECULAR BIOLOGY, VILNIUS UNIVERSITY

Master's degree. Continued my internship at Thermo Fisher Scientific Baltics. The aims of Master research were to investigate the "antigenic" properties of the inert thermophilic protein and its modification possibilities, evaluate its adaptation in antibody-based PCR.

### 2012 - 2016

# **MOLECULAR BIOLOGY, VILNIUS UNIVERSITY**

Bachelor's degree. I was chosen for best-in-class internship at Thermo Fisher Scientific Baltics. The aim of Bachelor research project was to clone, express and purify the functionally active bacterial ExoVII enzyme.

### I HAVE:

- Hands-on experience with various molecular biology methods
- Experience working according to GMP requirements

- Analytical mindset
- Motivation to learn
- Ability to work under time pressure.